bikefit.com 2018-06-29

# BikeFit's Privacy Policy

**BikeFit is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected.   **

Thank you for visiting BikeFit.com. The privacy policy below tells you how we use personal information collected at this site. Please read this privacy policy before using the site or submitting any personal information. By using the site, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive basis. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

With respect to applicable laws, this privacy policy also will alert you to any particular and additional information and rights you have pursuant to the General Data Protection Regulation effective 25 May 2018 (“GDPR”) that are applicable to information that BikeFit may collect from you (or “Personal Data” under GDPR) if you are located in the European Union GDPR. Under GDPR you are defined as a “Data Subject” and BikeFit is a “Data Controller” for Personal Data that BikeFit obtains and “Processes” pursuant to this policy.  

This policy applies to information we collect:

  * On the " **Sites** " \-- [BikeFit.com](http://www.bikefit.com/) and [Blog.BikeFit.com](http://blog.bikefit.com/) only. For links to other websites, please review the privacy policies posted on those sites.
  * Through mobile and desktop applications you download from the iTunes Store and the Google Play Store.  This includes the "BikeFit Pro App" and the "FootFit Calculator."  
  * From third parties, whether they are partners or vendors.

**Note:** the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for [BikeFit.com](http://www.bikefit.com/) and [Blog.BikeFit.com](http://blog.bikefit.com/) only. For links to other websites, please review the privacy policies posted on those sites.

##### GDPR Lawful Bases for Processing Personal Data of Data Subjects (This only applies to EU Citizens)

Under GDPR, Bikefit may only Process the Personal Data of a Data Subject lawfully if BikeFit has at least one of six lawful bases for Processing the Personal Data. Currently, under this version of the privacy policy, BikeFit relies on at least one of the following legal bases to process Personal Data under GDPR:

  * In order to perform pursuant to one or more legal agreements (contracts) with you,
  * With your consent, and
  * Pursuant to a Legitimate Interest, in which BikeFit considers the purpose it has for Processing your Personal Data, whether the Processing is necessary for that Purpose, and whether your own personal interests as a Data Subject outweigh BikeFit purpose in Processing your Personal Data.

(As a reminder, if you are not a Data Subject providing your Personal Data to Moz from within the European Union, GDPR does not apply to you.)  

**Collection of Information--What we Collect  
**We collect personally identifiable information:

  * Name
  * Contact information including e-mail address, phone number, address...etc (personal information).
  * Business name if applicable.
  * Payment information if a purchase is completed.  This information is not shared with any party and is protected via our Gateway systems Authorize.net and Paypal.  Please see their privacy policies for more information.

**How we collect this information:**

  * Directly from you when you provide it to us.  The information you provide is used to fulfill your specific request (typically an order). This information is only used to fulfill your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner, for example, to add you to our mailing list.
  * Automatically as you navigate through the site using cookies and other tracking technologies. Information collected automatically may include usage details, email address, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies and other tracking technologies.

**Cookie/Tracking Technology    
**[BikeFit.com](http://www.bikefit.com/) and [Blog.BikeFit.com](http://blog.bikefit.com/) may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.'

##### 

**How We Use Your Information**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To present bikefit.com and blog.bikefit.com to you
  * To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
  * To provide you with notices about your subscriptions to our e-mail marketing (MailChimp) or the BikeFit App.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
  * To notify you about changes to our bikefit.com or blog.bikefit or any products or services we offer or provide through it.
  * To provide purchase confirmations and shipping information when purchases are completed.
  * To send you the information you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you.
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

**Distribution of Information**  
We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

**Duration of Data Storage  
**  
BikeFit will retain the data described in this policy indefinitely unless you contact us to have that information removed.  

**Your Legal Rights**

  1. Right of access. \- You have the right to request access to any of your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”)
  2. Right of data correction.  If your data is incorrect, you have the right to contact us to update the incorrect or incomplete data.  This data will need to be verified by you.
  3. The right to erasure of personal data.  You have the right to request erasure or deletion of the personal data we hold.  We may not be able to immediately enact this request if specific legal situations apply.  If so, we will notify you of these.
  4. The right to the restriction of processing. You have the right to block further use of your personal data.  BikeFit will continue to store your information but will not use it any further. 
  5. The right to be informed.  You have the right to be provided with information on the Personal Data we use.  This is clearly defined in the privacy policy but you may contact BikeFit if you have any questions.
  6. The right to data portability. You have the right to request the transfer of your information to a third party. 
  7. The right to object to processing. You have the right to object to certain types of processing, specifically ones used for marketing and e-mail marketing.
  8. The right to withdraw consent.  You have the right to withdraw consent of the use of your information at any time, including the use of your information for marketing purposes.

**How to Exercise your Rights  
**  
If you would like to exercise any of your rights listed above, have any questions or concerns or would like to express a complaint, please contact us directly via e-mail at support@bikefit.com

**Commitment to Data Security**

Your personally identifiable information is kept secure. Only authorized BikeFit employees (whose employee contracts obligate them to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings.  We do **not** store your credit card information.

**Privacy Contact Information**  
If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy you may contact us here.

We reserve the right to make changes to this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted.  
This policy was last updated on 05/25/18
